on this video I would like to show you a
super useful new language that anyone
can learn and start to use in 10 minutes
or less the name of the language is D2
and it's a language we can use to
generate cool looking diagrams in no
time whether you are a developer product
manager marketer office worker or
student I am sure that in your career
you have needed to make a diagram a
diagram to explain a server architecture
a user flow a customer acquisition
funnel hiring process whatever we can
use a visual builder for this when we
drag and drop some boxes and connect
them with arrows and all that which I
find very time consuming or we can use
D2 to just describe what we want and get
an image out of it so let's see how the
language looks and what kind of diagrams
we can make we will start by defining
the actors in our diagram just by doing
this D2 will generate an image with each
actor inside of a Square now we can
create the connections between our
actors we can say that Steve Jobs is
connected to Apple as a Founder team
Cook is also connected to Apple as a CEO
apple is connected to the App Store as
their Monopoly Elon Musk is the owner of
Twitter which is distributed by the App
Store and finally we can say that both
Elon Musk and Tim Cook are friends that
code will generate an image Like This
Isn't that cool we are just writing down
names connections and labels and we are
getting a cool looking diagram with well
positioned arrows and boxes to connect
actors we have four options we can make
an arrow from A to B or no Arrow just a
connection between a and b and arrow
from B to a or a bi-directional arrow
between A and B to make our life easier
and clean up our code we can add
nicknames to our actors we can also
change the shapes of our actors if we
want to by doing nickname dot shape
here's a list of all the icons you can
use but if you don't like any of them
you can use your own images as well we
can also have containers which is a
shape inside of another shape like in
this example where we are grouping
compiled and interpreted programming
languages using container.child like for
example compiled that rust or
interpreted that JavaScript we can
connect items that are in separate
containers getting some cool looking
diagrams if we want to we can also
customize the style of our objects the
boxes as well as the style of the
connections the arrows we can make the
rust box the orange white text and 3D
and the connections to JavaScript to be
golden yellow and dashed if we want to
we can also add extra text to our
diagram we can use markdown and we can
even specify where we would like to put
it D2 is also super useful if you want
to make entity relationship diagrams for
SQL databases using the SQL table shape
we can diagram for example a simple SQL
that base with users and their tweets we
can specify the name of the columns
their type and we can also specify
constraints like primary key unique and
foreign key and we will get a
professional looking output like this
likewise if you are working with classes
and you need to create
uml diagrams for them you can use the
class shape D2 will automatically detect
what is a property and what is a method
it will also render void on methods with
no return value another kind of diagram
that is a pain to create manually is a
sequence diagram which thankfully is
really easy to make using D2 first we
have to use the shape sequence diagram
and then we can just write down
connections and their labels and after
that all the connections between objects
and their labels will be displayed in a
sequence D2 is very customizable you can
customize the direction of your diagram
and choose between up down left and
right you can also choose between
different color themes and my favorite
thing of oil you can also give your
diagrams the sketch style which makes it
look like it has been hand drawn V2
supports all the layout engines as well
the default one is called dagger they
also have elk and they have tala which
is paid but it makes the diagrams look
very very good to get started with D2
you can download it to your machine
using the terminal or you can go to
play.d2lang.com where you can write a
code on the browser and Export images
without having to download anything
thank you for watching this video I hope
you found it useful I was so happy to
discover D2 and I'm sure I will be using
it when explaining things on videos for
the channel let me know in the comments
what do you think about Vito and if you
see yourself using it anytime soon and
please don't forget that if you want to
learn things like JavaScript python
react react native gold Dart flutter
among many others for absolutely free
all you have to do is click the link
below to join any of our many free
course courses that you can take right
now for free with me click the link
below and I will see you there
see you on the next one bye
[Music]